Andy McDonald

Software developer

I am a software developer, a recent graduate of the Founders and Coders bootcamp in London and a former journalist. Currently seeking a full-time junior developer role.

Email: andy.william.mcdonald@gmail.com GitHub: github.com/andy-mc-donald LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/andy-mc-donald

Portfolio: andy-mcdonald-react-portfolio.netflify.com

Skills

Languages

JavaScript / ES6, HTML, CSS

Frameworks and Libraries

Node.js, React, Express, Handlebars, Sass, Styled Components, Material UI

Testing / Continuous Integration

Tape, Supertest, Travis CI

Devops

Git, GitHub, Netlify, Heroku

Methodology

Agile, Functional Programming, Test-Driven Development (TDD),

Databases

PostgreSQL

Design

Figma, Canva

Software Development Experience

New Statesman / Junior Software Developer (Freelance)

NOV 2019 - JAN 2020, LONDON

Freelance project for the New Statesman, working with their marketing and digital teams to create targeted front-end campaigns for the NS website in the run-up to the general election and Christmas.

Founders and Coders / Student

JUL 2019 - NOV 2019, LONDON

Full-time peer-led coding bootcamp focused on modern web development using front- and back-end Javascript. During the course I worked with frameworks and libraries including Node, React, Express, Sass and Styled Components, as well as PostgreSQL databases. Emphasis on TDD methodology, Agile development and version control using Git and GitHub.

Selected Projects:

UpSkillMe

Tech stack: React, Styled Components, Airtable

Food Miles

Tech stack: Handlebars, Node, Express, Sass, PostgreSQL, Tape, SuperTest

• Bugbears

Tech stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, PostgreSQL, Bcrypt, Tape

Project Fear

Tech stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, SuperTest, Nock

(See portfolio for more projects and information)

Self-Guided Learning / Student

AUG 2018 - PRESENT, LONDON

Before joining Founders and Coders I taught myself the fundamentals of JavaScript, HTML and CSS while working full time using various online resources, including FreeCodeCamp and Codewars.

Previous Work Experience

Freelance Writer

OCT 2017 - JUL 2019, LONDON

Freelance journalist and copywriter for clients including Viacom / Channel 5, Broadcast, Videonet (Mediatel), Television Business International (Informa Tech), K7 Media and various PR agencies.

Digital TV Europe (Informa Tech) / Deputy Editor

FEB 2013 - OCT 2017, LONDON

Full-time role as deputy editor of DigitalTVEurope. At DTVE I interviewed a number of high-profile industry figures from the TV, video and broadcasting space and covered emerging tech like virtual reality.

C21 Media / Senior Reporter

APR 2011 - FEB 2013, LONDON

Senior reporter contributing online and print articles for TV trade magazine C21. I was the lead contributor for C21's FutureMedia title and worked across C21's sister website TechCityInsider.

StrategyEye / Reporter, Senior Reporter

NOV 2007 - APR 2011, LONDON

Education

Founders and Coders / Software Development Bootcamp

JUL 2019 - NOV 2019, LONDON

Founders and Coders is a UK-based nonprofit organisation offering a full-time 18 week web development course in JavaScript, Node, Express, React, PostgreSQL, Handlebars, HTML, and CSS.

The University of Sheffield / MA Web Journalism

SEP 2006 - OCT 2007, SHEFFIELD

Vocational journalism course with a focus on online production skills. NCTJ pre-entry exams passed in news writing, media law and public administration.

The University of York / BA English Literature (2.1)

SEP 2002 - OCT 2005, YORK